Guide to the Men of All Colors Together/New York records,1980-2006.
Men of All Colors Together/New York records, 1980-2006
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Men of All Colors Together/New York records, 1980-2006.
7576
Men of All Colors Together/New York.
2.4 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the organization Men of All Colors Together/New York (MACT/NY) since its founding in 1980.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Men of All Colors Together/New York (MACT/NY) is a multiracial, multicultural organization of gay and bisexual men in New York City committed to addressing and combating racism and discrimination in the lesbian and gay male community and to providing a supportive environment for non-oppressive multiracial relating among gay men. Started under the name Black and White Men Together/New York, the organization maintains links with the National Association of Black and White Men Together (NABWMT). Mike Smith started BWMT San Francisco in February 1980, and Henry Wiemhoff organized the first meeting of BWMT/NY on June 6, 1980. The first issue of the BWMT/NY Information Bulletin, a two-page mimeographed newsletter, appeared a few weeks later, and Lidell Jackson soon took over as editor.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the organization Men of All Colors Together/New York (MACT/NY) since its founding in 1980, including Board minutes, treasurer's reports, photographs and slides of events and board members (many by photographer Robert Giard and member James Toms), files on their 1992-1994 venture, the Whole Health Support Group, to provide support to people with HIV/AIDS, and communication with other chapters of the National Association of Black and White Men Together, including People of All Colors Together (PACT) in Newark, NJ. Its NABWMT files include records of the New York sponsored annual conference in 1986. Also, a subject file arranged alphabetically that includes the incorporation papers and bylaws, notes on the history of the organization, files on deceased members, flyers and other files on events, clippings and press releases, and other documentation of the group's activities. The collection contains an incomplete set of the MACT/NY Bulletin, starting with number 5 from September 1980. Member files include press releases, fund raising announcements, calendars, and social event tickets from 1981-1983 saved by Bruce Voeller. The special correspondence folder includes letters from writer Audre Lorde and South African anti-apartheid and gay rights activist Tseko Simon Nkoli and a letter to choreographer Arnie Zane.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Men of All Colors Together/New York.; BWMT/NY.; National Association of Black and White Men Together.; People of All Colors Together (Newark, N.J.)
Subjects:
African American gays--New York (N.Y.).; AIDS (Disease)--Patients--Counseling of--New York (N.Y.).; Gay male couples--New York (N.Y.).; Gays--Political activity--New York (N.Y.).; Interracial dating--Social conditions.; Race identity--United States.; Racism--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Membership lists in box 3 are restricted for 80 years from date of creation.
PROVENANCE
Bruce Voeller donated his member files in 1988. Officers of MACT/NY donated the organizational records in 2006.
RELATED MATERIALS
Information Bulletin (MACT/NY).
Black and White Men Together (Atlanta, GA.) records, Atlanta History Center.
Men of All Colors Together Boston records, #M68, Northeastern University Archives and Special Collections.
Black and White Men Together-Milwaukee records, #208, Wisconsin Historical Society, Milwaukee Archives Research Center.
Black & White Men Together - Records, #1991-04, and NABWMT Records, #2001-21, GLBT Historical Society, San Francisco.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Board Minutes
Box 1
Series II. Treasurers' Files
Boxes 1,3
Series III. Membership Files
Box 3
Series IV. Alphabetical Subject Files
Boxes 1,2
Series V. Whole Health Support Group, 1992-1994
Box 2
Series VI. NABWMT and other local BWMT/MACT/PACT chapters, including PACT Newark
Box 2
Series VII. Photographs
Box 4
Series VIII. Member Files
Box 4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Board Minutes
  - Board, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board--Early Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board Minutes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board Minutes, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board Minutes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board Minutes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board Minutes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board Minutes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board Minutes, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board Minutes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board Minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board Minutes, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board Minutes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board Minutes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board Minutes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board Minutes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Board Minutes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Board Minutes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board Minutes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board Minutes, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Board Minutes, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Board of Directors Roster (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series II. Treasurers' Files
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Financial Report NY Dept. of State IRS, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Treasurer's Reports (redacted), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Treasurer's Reports (originals) [ RESTRICTED], 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports (redacted), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Treasurer's Reports (originals)[ RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's Reports (redacted), 2002 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Treasurer's Reports (originals)[ RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Circle Line Sightseeing Yachts (financial arrangements), 1986-1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Attendance Records and Center Rent, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - North Star Fund Grant Applications, 1981-1994 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Funding Exchange Grant Inquiry, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Other Grants, 1998, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Treasurer's Log [ RESTRICTED], c.1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Financial, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series III. Membership Files
  - Membership Lists [ RESTRICTED], 1984-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Membership Lists (Computer Printouts and CD)[ RESTRICTED], 2000-2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Membership and Deposits [ RESTRICTED], 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series IV. Alphabetical Subject Files
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Agendas, Organizational Files (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bequests, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Brochures (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Calendars (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Coalitions and Joint Activities, 1982-1998 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Committees, 1985-1996 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Computer discs and lists of contents (printouts are found in the next few files as well as throughout the collection according to subject) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Computer Printouts: Documents (incl. Board of Directors Agendas and Minutes, 2001-2006 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Computer Printouts: Email, 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Computer Printouts: Membership, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Computer Printouts: Old Files\Program (Board of Directors Minutes, annual meeting 1997, Oct. 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Computer Printouts: Old Files\WPDOCS (Board of Directors Minutes, annual meeting 1994), 1994-Jul. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Consciousness-Raising (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1984-2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, Special, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Credle, James, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Credle, James and Karp, Mitchell: Making Multiculturalism a Reality, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Deceased Members/Others, 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Events/Flyers, 1981-2002 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Family Protection Act, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Glover, Tony, 1993,1997 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Grassroots Victory Award (Funding Exchange) (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - History, 1984-1997 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - History (Transcript of MACT History Night), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - HIV/AIDS, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Incorporation, Bylaws, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - IRS, 1985-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jacks of Color, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kwanzaa, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lavender Light Choir, 1985-93 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center, 1984-89 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Membership Mailings, 1987-2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Membership Survey, c.1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nkoli, Tseko Simon, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Other Organizations, 1980-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Press Coverage, 1981-2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Press--Members and Friends, 1984-2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1980-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Protests, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Protest: Miss Saigon, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Racism (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Statements by Members, 1985-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Statements of Dissent, 1985-2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Statements of Purpose/Position Paper on Multiculturalism, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Statements on Procedures, c.1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - MACT Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series V. Whole Health Support Group, 1992-1994
  - Whole Health Contract, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Whole Health Support Group Contract, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Whole Health Publicity (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Whole Health--Correspondence with HIV CARE, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Whole Health Board of Directors (originals and computer printouts), 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Whole Health Reports to Board of Directors, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Whole Health Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Whole Health--Funding, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Whole Health--Financial, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Whole Health Monthly Fiscal Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Whole Health--IRS Information, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - NY State Charities Registration, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NY State Dept. of Labor, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - NY State--Withholding, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Workers' Compensation, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Revenue and Expense Report, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Whole Health--Check Register and Bank Reconciliation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Whole Health Bookkeeping/Audit, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Audits, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Whole Health: Payroll, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Whole Health Personnel, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Whole Health NYS Unemployment Insurance, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Whole Health Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Series VI. NABWMT and other local BWMT/MACT/PACT chapters, including PACT Newark
  - NABWMT/IABWMT, 1984-2005 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - NABWMT Correspondence/Relations, 1986-1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - IABWMT Convention (Washington, D.C.) (incl. a speech by Adrienne Rich), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - IABWMT Convention (Columbus, OH), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - NABWMT Convention (New York City), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - NABWMT Convention (Tallahassee, FL), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - NABWMT Convention (San Francisco), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - NABWMT Conventions, 1984-1995 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - NABWMT--MRMCI (Multiracial/Multicultural Institute), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - NABWMT Quarterly/Colorful People and Places (catalogued separately), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Other Chapters (Baltimore, Chicago, Detroit, Milwaukee, Philadelphia), 1985-2002 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - PACT Newark, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PACT Newark, 1994-2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PACT Newark, 1995-2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series VII. Photographs
  - Photos by Robert Giard (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Slide photographs by James Toms (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series VIII. Member Files
  - Voeller, Bruce: member files: BWMT/NY press releases and misc. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Anonymous member files: bibliographies, ca. 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Publications removed from collection 7576 - cataloged as individual books and serials in the Human Sexuality Collection
B&G, 1 issue.
Black and White Men Together/Atlanta Newsletter, 4 issues.
The Black Forum, 1 issue.
Black/Out, 1 issue.
BLK, 3 issues.
The Board Memo, 4 issues.
The Body Politic, 1 issue.
BWMT Detroit Newsletter, 4 issues.
BWMT/Los Angeles, 1 issue.
The BWMT/MACT Bridge (BWMT/MACT San Francisco Bay Area), 10 issues.
BWMT/MACT/NY Information Bulletin, almost complete 1980-2004.
BWMT/MACT Philadelphia/Challenger, 6 issues.
BWMT Memphis, 1 issue.
BWMT Tallahassee and Big Bend Florida, 2 issues.
The Center Voice, 4 issues.
Chorus Lines, 1 issue.
Color Life!, 1 issue.
Couples, 1 issue.
Gay Community News, 1 issue.
Glover, Tony, ed. Celebrating Diversity: A 10th Anniversary Journal of Poetry, Narrative, Essays and Photography. New York, NY: Men of All Colors Together/New York, Inc., 1993.
Glowletter, 1 issue.
GMAD Calendar, 5 issues.
Inside QGLU, 1 issue.
Lavender Left, 1 issue.
Lesbian & Gay New York, 1 issue.
The New York City News, 1 issue.
MACT Chicago, 4 issues.
Mallon, Gerald L., ed. Resisting Racism: An Action Guide. San Francisco: National Association of Black and White Men Together, 1984.
NABWMT Journal, 3 issues.
NABWMT News and Notes from the National Office, 1 issue.
NABWMT Quarterly, 33 issues.
News for the Hues (BWMT/PACT Baltimore), 1 issue.
OutWeek, 2 issues.
PACT/The PACT Beacon, 3 issues.
Pride Guide (Queens), 1 issue.
Quarterly, 1 issue.
Quarterly / National Association of Black and White Men Together and National Association of Black and White Men Together newsletter, 19 issues.
S.H.A.D.E.S. Newsletter, 1 issue.
Smith, Michael J. Colorful People and Places. San Francisco: Quarterly Press of BWMT, Inc., 1983.
Together (BWMT Washington, D.C.), 8 issues.